<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="about_close">Close</string>
    <string name="about_whoami">I am monerujo</string>
    <string name="about_version">Version %1$s (%2$d)</string>

    <string name="credits_text"><![CDATA[
        <b>Credits</b>
        <br/>
        m2049r, baltsar777, anhdres, keejef,
        rehrar, EarlOfEgo, ErCiccione et al.
        <br/><br/>
        <a href="https://monerujo.io/">monerujo.io</a>
        ]]></string>

    <string name="privacy_policy"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Privacy Policy</h1>
        <p>This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection,
        use and disclosure of personal information we receive from users of our
        app (monerujo: Monero Wallet).
        </p>
        <p>By using the app, you agree to the collection and use of information in
        accordance with this policy.
        </p>
        <h2>Data Collected</h2>
        <p>Personal data is any kind of data that could identify an individual.
        </p>
        <p>Monero keys and public addresses are collected and processed by the app locally
        for the purpose of processing transactions and transmitted into the Monero Network
        in encrypted form.
        </p>
        <p>Other personal data is not collected by the app.</p>
        <p>If you use the exchange (optional) functionality, monerujo fetches the exchange
        rate through the public API of coinmarketcap.com.
        See their privacy policy at https://coinmarketcap.com/privacy for
        details on how data in your requests is collected.</p>
        <p>If you use the app to pay to BTC addresses, you will be using the XMR.TO service.
        See their privacy policy at https://xmr.to/ for details. Monerujo send them the BTC
        destination address and amount. Your IP will also be collectable.</p>
        <h2>App Permissions</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>INTERNET : Connect to the Monero Network via a Monero Daemon Node</li>
        <li>READ_EXTERNAL_STORAGE : Read wallet files stored on the device</li>
        <li>WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE : Write wallet files stored on the device</li>
        <li>WAKE_LOCK : Keep device awake while syncing</li>
        <li>CAMERA : Scan QR Codes for receiving Monero</li>
        </ul>
        <h2>Changes to this Privacy Policy</h2>
        <p>We may update this privacy policy from time to time. We will notify
        you of any changes by posting the new privacy policy in the app and on the
        website (www.monerujo.io)
        You are advised to review this privacy policy periodically for any changes.
        <p>This Privacy Policy was last updated: 10th November, 2017.
        </p>
        <h2>Contact Us</h2>
        <p>If you have any questions about our privacy policy,
        or how your data is being collected and processed,
        please e-mail privacy@monerujo.io.
        </p>
        ]]></string>
</resources>
