<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools" tools:locale="en">
    <string name="about_close">மூடு</string>
    <string name="about_whoami">நான் monerujo</string>
    <string name="about_version">பதிப்பு %1$s (%2$d)</string>

    <string name="credits_text"><![CDATA[
        <b>நன்றி</b>
        <br/>
        m2049r, baltsar777, anhdres, keejef,
        rehrar, EarlOfEgo, ErCiccione et al.
        <br/><br/>
        <a href="https://monerujo.io/">monerujo.io</a>
        ]]></string>

    <string name="privacy_policy"><![CDATA[
        <h1>தனியுரிமை கொள்கை</h1>
        <p>This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection,
        use and disclosure of personal information we receive from users of our
        app (monerujo: மொனேரொ பணப்பை).
        </p>
        <p>இந்த செயலியை பயன்படுத்துவதன் மூலம், நீங்கள் இந்தக் கொள்கையின்படி தகவலைச் சேகரிப்பதற்கும் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கும் ஒப்புக்கொள்கிறீர்கள்
        </p>
        <h2>சேகரிக்கப்படும் தரவுகள்</h2>
        <p>தனிநபரை அடையாளம் காட்டவல்ல எந்தவொரு தரவும் தனிப்பட்ட தரவாகும்.
        </p>
        <p>Monero keys and public addresses are collected and processed by the app locally
        for the purpose of processing transactions and transmitted into the Monero Network
        in encrypted form.
        </p>
        <p>மற்ற எந்தவொரு தனிப்பட்ட தரவுகளும் இந்த செயலியால் சேகரிக்கப்படுவதில்லை.</p>
        <p>If you use the exchange (optional) functionality, monerujo fetches the exchange
        rate through the public API of coinmarketcap.com.
        See their privacy policy at https://coinmarketcap.com/privacy for
        details on how data in your requests is collected.</p>
        <p>If you use the app to pay to BTC addresses, you will be using the SideShift.ai service.
        See their privacy policy at https://sideshift.ai/ for details. Monerujo send them the BTC
        destination address and amount. Your IP will also be collectable.</p>
        <h2>செயலி அனுமதிகள்</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>INTERNET (இணையம்) : ஒரு மொனேரொ மறைநிரல் கணுவை கொண்டு மொனேரொ வலையமைப்போடு இணைப்பதற்கு</li>
        <li>READ_EXTERNAL_STORAGE (புற சேமிப்பகத்தை படித்தல்) : சாதனத்தில் சேமித்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருக்கும் பணப்பை கோப்புகளை படிப்பதற்கு</li>
        <li>WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE (புற சேமிப்பகத்தில் எழுதுதல்) : சாதனத்தில் சேமித்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருக்கும் பணப்பை கோப்புகளை எழுதுவதற்கு</li>
        <li>WAKE_LOCK (திரை விழிப்பு பூட்டு) : ஒத்திசைக்கும்போது சாதனத்தை விழிப்போடு வைத்திருப்பதற்கு</li>
        <li>CAMERA (படமி) : மொனேரொவை பெறுதல் பொருட்டு QR குறியீடுகளை வருடுவதற்கு</li>
        </ul>
        <h2>இந்த தனியுரிமை கொள்கைகளில் ஏற்படும் மாற்றங்கள்</h2>
        <p>We may update this privacy policy from time to time. We will notify
        you of any changes by posting the new privacy policy in the app and on the
        website (www.monerujo.io)
        You are advised to review this privacy policy periodically for any changes.
        <p>This Privacy Policy was last updated: 10th November, 2017.
        </p>
        <h2>Contact Us</h2>
        <p>If you have any questions about our privacy policy,
        or how your data is being collected and processed,
        please e-mail privacy@monerujo.io.
        </p>
        ]]></string>
</resources>
