<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="help_create_new"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Create Wallet - New</h1>
        <p>If you need a new Monero Address!</p>
        <p>Enter a unique wallet name and password.
        The password is used for securing your wallet data on the device. Use a strong password -
        even better use a passphrase.</p>
        <h2>Note your Mnemonic Seed!</h2>
        <p>On the following screen you will find your 25-word \"Mnemonic Seed\".
        This is the only data needed to recover your wallet at a later point
        and gain full access to your funds.
        Keeping this secure and private is very important, as it gives <em>anyone</em>
        full access to your funds!</p>
        <p>If you lose your wallet password, you can still recover your wallet with the Mnemonic Seed.</p>
        <p>There is no way to recover your Mnemonic Seed, if you lose it all your funds will be lost!
        The Mnemonic Seed can also never be changed, and if it is stolen or otherwise compromised,
        you will have to move your funds to new wallet (with a new Mnemonic Seed). Therefore, it is best
        that you backup your Mnemonic Seed by writing it down and storing it in <em>multiple</em> safe
        and secure places.</p>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="help_create_seed"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Create Wallet - Seed</h1>
        <p>If you already have a Monero Address and want to recover the transactions from the blockchain!</p>
        <p>Enter a unique wallet name and password. The password is used for securing your wallet data on the device.
        Use a strong password - even better use a passphrase.</p>
        <p>Enter your Seed in the field \"Mnemonic Seed\".<p>
        <p>If you know the block number of the first transaction used for this address, enter it in the
        field \"Restore Height\" - leaving it blank will scan the <em>entire</em> blockchain for
        transactions belonging to your address. This takes a <em>long</em> time.</p>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="help_create_keys"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Create Wallet - Keys</h1>
        <p>If you are recovering your wallet using your keys!</p>
        <p>Enter a unique wallet name and password. The password is used for securing your wallet data on the device.
        Use a strong password - even better use a passphrase.<p>
        <p>Enter your Monero Address in the field \"Public Address\" and fill out \"View Key\" and  \"Spend Key\".</p>
        <p>If you know the block number of the first transaction used for this address, enter it in the
        field \"Restore Height\" - leaving it blank will scan the <em>entire</em> blockchain for
        transactions belonging to your address. This takes a <em>long</em> time.</p>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="help_create_view"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Create Wallet - View</h1>
        <p>If you just want to monitor incoming transactions to a wallet!</p>
        <p>Enter a unique wallet name and password. The password is used for securing your wallet data on the device.
        Use a strong password - even better use a passphrase.<p>
        <p>Enter your Monero Address in the field \"Public Address\" and fill out the \"View Key\".</p>
        <p>If you know the block number of the first transaction used for this address, enter it in the
        field \"Restore Height\" - leaving it blank will scan the <em>entire</em> blockchain for
        transactions belonging to your address. This takes a <em>long</em> time.</p>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="help_details"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Wallet Details</h1>
        <h2>Public address</h2>
        Your public address is like your bank account number you can share this with anyone without
        having to fear losing your Monero. People will send Monero to your wallet using this address.
        <h2>Mnemonic Seed</h2>
        This is the only data needed to recover your wallet at a later point and gain full access to
        your funds. Keeping this private and secure is very important, as it gives <em>anyone</em> full
        access to your Monero! If you haven’t written this down somewhere safe please do!
        <h2>View key</h2>
        Your view key can be used to monitor incoming transactions to your wallet without giving
        permission to spend the funds inside your wallet.
        <h2>Spend key</h2>
        Your spend key allows anyone to spend the Monero associated with your wallet, so don’t tell
        anyone this key, keep it safe like your Mnemonic Seed.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="help_list"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Wallet List</h1>
        <h2>Node</h2>
        <p>Monerujo uses a Remote Node to communicate with the Monero Network without having
        to download and store a copy of the whole blockchain itself. You can find a list of popular
        remote nodes or learn how to run your own remote node here https://moneroworld.com/<p>
        <p>Monerujo comes with some Remote Nodes preset. It remembers the last five nodes used.</p>
        <h2>Wallets</h2>
        <p>Here you see your wallets. They are located in the <tt>monerujo</tt> folder
        in the internal storage of your device. You can use a file explorer app to see them.
        You should make backups of this folder on a regular basis to off-device storage in
        case your device explodes or gets stolen.</p>
        <p>Select a wallet to open it or press the \"+\" to create a new one.
        Or select one of the wallet operations:</p>
        <h3>Details</h3>
        <p>Show the wallet details, seed &amp; keys.</p>
        <h3>Receive</h3>
        <p>Make a QR code for receiving Moneroj.</p>
        <h3>Rename</h3>
        <p>Rename the wallet. Backups are not renamed.</p>
        <h3>Backup</h3>
        <p>Make a copy of the wallet in the <tt>backups</tt> folder inside the <tt>monerujo</tt>
        overwriting previous copies there.</p>
        <h3>Archive</h3>
        <p>Make a backup and delete the wallet afterwards. The copy remains in the <tt>backups</tt>
        folder. If you no longer need your backups you should delete them with a file explorer or
        secure delete app.</p>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="help_wallet"><![CDATA[
        <h1>The Wallet</h1>
        <h2>Scanning</h2>
        Because Monero likes to keep things private, every time you open a Monerujo wallet we have to
        scan the blockchain to see if any new Moneroj have been sent to your wallet, this only
        stores information to your phone which belongs to your wallet. Sometimes it can take a while
        because you haven’t synced in a long time.
        <h2>The Balance</h2>
        <p><b>Help! My wallet balance has disappeared or is unconfirmed!</b><br/>
        Don’t panic! When you send funds from your wallet, some of your balance will temporarily show
        as unconfirmed.
        This happens as a result of how Monero is exchanged on the blockchain and how change works.
        Read more about change at https://getmonero.org/resources/moneropedia/change.html
        <h2>Transaction List</h2>
        <p>A list of the wallet transactions. In view wallets, only incoming transactions are shown.</p>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="help_tx_details"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Transaction Details</h1>
        <h2>Destination</h2>
        This is the public address of the wallet you sent Monero to
        <h2>PaymentID</h2>
        You can use a Payment ID to identify the reason you sent Monero between two parties this is
        fully optional and private. For example it can allow a Business to reconcile your transaction
        with an item you bought.
        <h2>TX ID</h2>
        This is your Transaction ID you can use it to identify your obfuscated transaction on a Monero
        Blockchain explorer like <a href="https://xmrchain.net/">https://xmrchain.net/</a>
        <h2>TX KEY (Transaction Key)</h2>
        This is your transaction private key, keep this safe as revealing this to a third party
        reveals which signature in a ring is yours, thereby making your transaction transparent.
        <h2>Block</h2>
        This was the block your transaction was included in.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="help_send"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Send</h1>
        <h2>Receiver’s address</h2>
        <p>This is the public address of the wallet you are sending Moneroj to, you can copy this from
        your clipboard, scan a QR code or enter it manually. Make sure you triple check this to
        ensure you aren’t sending coins to the wrong address.</p>
        <p>In addition to sending XMR, you can send BTC through the XMR.TO service (see https://xmr.to
        for details). See the section on sending BTC below.</p>
        <h2>Payment ID</h2>
        <p>You can use a Payment ID to identify the reason you sent Monero between two parties. This
        is fully optional and private. For example it can allow a business to reconcile your
        transaction with an item you bought.<p>
        <h2>Ring size</h2>
        <p>There are a number of ring sizes to choose from in Monerujo. If you are a beginner user
        we recommend you stick with a ring size of 7. Increasing the ring size above 7 increases
        the amount of signers in a ring signature, theoretically providing increased plausible
        deniability. However setting high ring sizes can also make your transaction stand out on
        the blockchain.</p>
        <h2>Priority</h2>
        <p>This setting determines the speed at which your transaction will be included in the
        blockchain. A high priority setting will correlate directly with a higher transaction fee
        and the inverse is true for a low priority. Please note that if you set your transaction to
        a low priority it can be hours before it is included on the blockchain. The default priority
        is \"Medium\".</p>
        <h1>Sending BTC</h1>
        <h2>XMR.TO</h2>
        <p>XMR.TO is a third party service which acts as an exchange from Monero to Bitcoin.
        We use the XMR.TO API to integrate Bitcoin payments into Monerujo. Please check out
        https://xmr.to and decide for yourself if this is something you want to use. The Monerujo
        Team is not associated with XMR.TO and cannot help you with their service.</p>
        <h2>XMR.TO Exchange Rate<h2>
        <p>On the \"Amount\" screen you will be shown the current parameters of the XMR.TO service. These
        include the current exchange rate as well as upper and lower BTC limits. Note that this
        rate is not guaranteed at this point. You will also see
        the amount up to which the BTC transaction will be executed instantly without waiting for
        XMR confirmations (see the XMR.TO FAQ for more details). Please note, that XMR.TO does
        not charge extra fees - how cool is that?</p>
        <h2>XMR.TO Order<h2>
        <p>On the \"Confirm\" screen, you will see the actual XMR.TO order. This order is valid for
        a limited time - you may notice a countdown on the \"Spend\" button. The exchange rate may
        be different to the indicative one shown on previous screens.</p>
        <h2>XMR.TO Secret Key<h2>
        <p>Since Monerujo only handles the Monero part of your transaction your XMR.TO secret key
        can be used to track the Bitcoin part of your order on the XMR.TO homepage.</p>
        <p>Please note, that this secret key is only valid for 24 hours after the transaction is
        started!</p>
        <h2>XMR.TO Countdown!</h2>
        <p>Once the countdown reaches zero, you need to get a new quote from XMR.TO by going back to the
        previous step and then coming back to the \"Confirm\" screen.</p>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="help_xmrto"><![CDATA[
        <h1>Sending BTC</h1>
        <h2>XMR.TO</h2>
        <p>XMR.TO is a third party service which acts as an exchange from Monero to Bitcoin.
        We use the XMR.TO API to integrate Bitcoin payments into Monerujo. Please check out
        https://xmr.to and decide for yourself if this is something you want to use. The Monerujo
        Team is not associated with XMR.TO and cannot help you with their service.</p>
        <h2>XMR.TO Exchange Rate<h2>
        <p>On the \"Amount\" screen you will be shown the current parameters of the XMR.TO service. These
        include the current exchange rate as well as upper and lower BTC limits. Note that this
        rate is not guaranteed at this point. You will also see
        the amount up to which the BTC transaction will be executed instantly without waiting for
        XMR confirmations (see the XMR.TO FAQ for more details). Please note, that XMR.TO does
        not charge extra fees - how cool is that?</p>
        <h2>XMR.TO Order<h2>
        <p>On the \"Confirm\" screen, you will see the actual XMR.TO order. This order is valid for
        a limited time - you may notice a countdown on the \"Spend\" button. The exchange rate may
        be different to the indicative one shown on previous screens.</p>
        <h2>XMR.TO Secret Key<h2>
        <p>Since Monerujo only handles the Monero part of your transaction your XMR.TO secret key
        can be used to track the Bitcoin part of your order on the XMR.TO homepage.</p>
        <p>Please note, that this secret key is only valid for 24 hours after the transaction is
        started!</p>
        <h2>XMR.TO Countdown!</h2>
        <p>Once the countdown reaches zero, you need to get a new quote from XMR.TO by going back to the
        previous step and then coming back to the \"Confirm\" screen.</p>
    ]]></string>

</resources>
